Los Angeles, CA, USA +1 (919) 904-2124 karataev.dima@gmail.com

Dmytro Karataiev

adkdevelopment.com github.com/dmytroKarataiev linkedin.com/in/dmytrokarataiev

Summary:

Android developer with portfolio of open-source applications published on Google Play and interested in the field of Machine Learning. Also have extensive experience in marketing, including successful portfolio management and new brands launches with focus on digital activities.

Technical Skills

Languages: Java, Python.

Databases/Other: Realm, SQLite, Git/GitHub, Gradle.

Exposed to: JavaScript, PHP, CSS3.

Project Experience

BBC News Reader - GitHub Page - Google Play

August 2016

- RSS news reader for the BBC XML feed.
- Uses MVP Architecture, Realm database, JobScheduler, Retrofit, RxJava.

Earthquake Survival - GitHub Page - Google Play

April 2016 - Present

- Earthquake monitoring application with survival information, notifications, auto syncs.
- Uses SyncAdapter, ContentProvider, Loaders, Maps, Locations, Geofences, Notifications.

Flashlight with Morse - GitHub Page - Google Play

January 2016

- Flashlight application with simple design, fast speed, Morse code and Emergency Signal.
- Works as Service with all the tasks on background thread (Service, Camera2 API).

Popular Movies - GitHub Page - Google Play

December 2015 - Present

- Fast and efficient client to The Movie Database with Search and Favorites functionality and tablet design.
- Uses RecyclerView, AsyncTasks, Fragments, Content Provider, Database, CursorAdapter, YouTube API.

Connect Four Game - GitHub Page - Google Play

November 2015

- Hard solved Android game with different Al's, two-player mode.
- Real-Time Multiplayer, Achievements through Google Play Services.

Work Experience

Freelance – Android Developer

Los Angeles, USA | August 2014 – Present

- Writing Android application for clients according to their requirements.
- Working under NDA on one big health-related project and as a tester for an Android MOOC platform.
- Contributing to several open-source projects on GitHub.

Yalantis – Android Intern – GitHub Page

Dnipro, Ukraine | February 2016 – June 2016

- Created three Android applications with an increasing level of complexity.
- Used technologies: MVP Architecture, RxJava, Retrofit, Facebook API, Dagger 2, etc.

DANONE Nutricia – Marketing, Strategy and Insights Manager

Kyiv, Ukraine | April 2013 – August 2014

- Managed portfolio of 3 brands, achieved 2nd position in the Value Market Share (+700bps Year on Year).
- Launched portfolio extension (new 9 SKU's +33%), managed Social Media campaigns.

Unilever – Brand Manager

Kyiv, Ukraine | July 2010 – April 2013

- Achieved 1st place in Volume/Value Market Shares (+1000bps), launched new brand, 40 additional SKU's.
- Managed several cross-country projects (Russia Ukraine Belarus), led workshops for sales team.

Education

Udacity – Machine Learning Engineer Nanodegreeexp. Sept 2016Udacity – Android Nanodegree – Verified CertificateApril 2016Taurida National University, Simferopol, Ukraine – Political Science, M.A., GPA 3.57June 2010

Certificates

Coursera University of Michigan – Programming in Python (4 courses)

Coursera Stanford – Algorithms and Analysis (Part 1)

edX MIT – 6.00.1x, 6.00.2x Computer Science and Python Programming

edX Harvard CS50x – Intro to Computer Science

July 2015 – November 2015

Honors and Activities

Udacity Transcend Award - Link

June 2016

Choice of the year award for the best brand in the market (2011, 2012)

December 2011, December 2012

First prize and diploma for the best paper – Moscow State University International Conference

April 2010